Memories from ten years ago...
The words of the
man who was my dad...
Even if I was a mistake from the
beginning, the path I've chosen isn't.
I wanted that event to be
more than just a tragic backstory.
That's why I yearned to
become a champion of justice.
For over ten years,
I've clung to the ideal
of a world where everyone is
happy and no one needs to cry.
So it was clear from the
beginning what I needed to do.
I didn't fight because
I became a Master.
I decided to fight because it
was something that I could do.
Something I
believed I ought to do.
Tohsaka...
Hidden in my left hand
My wishes stay unfulfilled
Stuck in an unending dream
Hidden in my right hand
My hollow memories
stay invisible to all
Being pelted by an unending rain
Be it the strength to
protect what's precious
Or the weakness
to lose faith in it
I'll accept it all
And look for a new dawn
When I reach
out, I see the light
In tatters, you
still save my life
All the feelings
poured into the tip
Of the blade held aloft
A prayer that transcends time
Where are you?
Time of Departure
How valiant.
You can continue to
defy me all you like,
but your Servant
body cannot resist me.
Surely you can sense my Command Spells
eating away at you, little by little.
Would it not be easier if you
simply gave in and submitted to me?
Oh, my stubborn Saber...
I'd like a girl like you.
With gold hair, a small body,
young and noble-minded like a boy.
It is admirable that you
choose death over betrayal.
I really want to trample on you.
I will make you become
my Servant of your own will.
Not your body, but I will start
by breaking down your heart.
What are you doing, Caster?
Souichirou-sama...
Why are you here?
I thought I requested for you
to remain at Ryuudou Temple.
Answer my
question first, Caster.
What are you doing here?
Yesterday, I seized the Servant of
Emiya Shirou, one of the other Masters.
He escaped just before I could
finish him, but he is no longer a Master.
I see.
But I do not remember
instructing you to do so.
I acted on my own
authority, Master.
I attacked this church in order
to obtain the Holy Grail's vessel
and slew the priest
who oversaw it,
but the Grail's whereabouts
remain unknown.
You failed to return because
you couldn't locate the Grail?
I get the gist of the situation.
Now, can you explain
why you acted on your own?
I apologize.
However, my actions were
all for your sake, Master.
My only goal is to help
you achieve victory.
I have no other purpose.
I see.
In that case, you
cannot leave this place.
Search it until
you are satisfied.
Until then, I will
also remain here.
No, that will not be
necessary, Master.
Locating the Holy Grail
will take some time.
It would be safer for you to
return to Ryuudou Temple.
A fair point.
But if I did so, I would be unable
to achieve my own objective.
Souichirou-sama, what is...
Be quick about it. If the
Grail isn't here, so be it.
I don't care how you accomplish
this task. All I need is the result.
When was it that I finally figured
out the true nature of that dream?
That it was a certain Heroic
Spirit's mental landscape.
Among the many Heroic
Spirits—the Servants...
there are special Servants that
are safeguards, called "Guardians."
They are summoned into the various ages
and prevent the human world's destruction.
Or, more accurately,
they counter the human
race's self-destruction.
Even though he was
summoned to save humanity,
before he could save them,
he was forced to shoulder
their countless mistakes.
It didn't take long for him
to determine that it was futile
and start despising
the human world.
In the end, he continued to be
betrayed by his ideal, even after death.
If you aren't feeling
well, we can put this off.
There's no pressing
need to attack right away.
No, if we know where Caster is,
we should deal with her at once.
Here.
So you just watched me sleep instead
of waking me? That's kinda creepy.
Relax.
I wouldn't dream of doing
something so improper.
I did overhear a
thing or two, though.
You muttered a few
rather harsh things,
like "This is so irritating"
and "I'm pissed."
Oh, that's a relief.
Say, Archer...
Have you ever regretted
the things you've done?
I want to do whatever I
can to avoid having regrets.
That's probably easier
said than done, though.
I bet it's even
harder than I imagine.
Some can do it, and some can't.
You strike me as
the former type.
Not only do such people
rarely make mistakes,
they don't dwell
on the ones they do.
Rin...
Brilliant people shine more
brightly than ordinary ones.
They never regret or agonize
over what they've done.
And you are most
definitely that sort of person.
Tohsaka Rin can believe in her own
path to the very end without regret.
What about you, then?
Will you be able to believe you made
the right choices until the very end?
I'm sorry, but that
question is meaningless.
Why?
Have you forgotten, Master?
My "end" came and went long ago.
Jeez... Where the
heck has she gone to?
Think hard about
where she is likely to go!
Damn it.
I don't have time
to cherry-pick.
He's the only person
she can rely on.
She attacked the overseer?
I'd say that's a bold move.
Kirei was probably
prepared for it, though.
Rin, I must ask you again.
What, you're still worried?
I'll take Caster on.
If you get too close, she might
use Rule Breaker on you too.
So I'll leave her
Master, Kuzuki, to you.
I'm fine with
taking on that man.
But do you understand that no
mage alive is a match for Caster?
Relax. If I didn't have a chance,
I wouldn't have suggested it.
You can leave her to me, Archer.
Very well. I'll believe in you.
All right, let's do this.
I'll take out Caster
here, no matter what.
And when I do, Saber will
probably return to normal
and be able to forge a
new pact with Shirou, right?
Did you kill Kirei?
Tohsaka...
Yes.
Seemed like he was not going to
give me the Grail without protesting.
That's good judgment.
So, did you make
sure he was dead?
Saber...
And what is that
supposed to mean?
Nothing.
If you didn't see his corpse,
he's still stubbornly clinging
to life somewhere. That's all.
But enough about him.
Let's get this over with.
This time, you don't have a human
shield, so I can go all out to beat you.
Do you think you can beat
me in a battle of magic?
It depends on how I go about it.
And thankfully, you don't seem
to have full control of Saber yet.
Plus, I also know how
strong Kuzuki-sensei is.
He's no match for my Archer.
Are you ready, Archer?
I am.
We proceed as
planned, then, Rin?
Yes.
Don't hold back.
I'm using everything I have!
How adorable.
You think you have a chance
against me one-on-one?
Are you forgetting
my trump card?
With my Command Spells, I can
make her my puppet here and now.
Were you to use one, Saber
would be able to resist it.
I don't know if it would
be for one minute or two,
but that's more than enough
time to take down the likes of you!
A flash spell?
I'll start by dragging
you down to Earth!
Archer!
Huh? Archer?
What do you think
you're doing, Archer?
You see, defeating her here
struck me as overly idealistic.
When it comes to escaping,
she's the best there is.
She even tore apart her own
younger brother to get away.
You talk as though
you know all about me.
Have you discerned
my true identity?
Familiars that use
dragon teeth as vessels
are the hallmark of the
King of Colchis's magic.
His daughter, Princess Medea,
was hailed as a witch without peer.
He can't seriously be...
If I may ask, Caster, do you
still have reserves to spare?
Archer, are you...
Of course!
I've stored sufficient mana to sustain
not only one more but all the Servants!
Then that simplifies things.
I will take you up on
your earlier offer, Caster.
Even though you
turned me down before?
The situation has changed.
Considering the advantage
that Saber confers,
isn't it only natural that
I should side with you?
I distrust traitors.
As well you should.
I'm only yielding to
you for my own benefit.
There is no trust
or loyalty in that.
But is that not how
Servants are by nature?
Very well.
I suppose I wouldn't be much of a
mage if I couldn't keep you under control.
Thus, I shall play
into your hands.
Tohsaka!
Trace...
on!
Shirou, you idiot!
What do you think you're doing?
So that appears to be that.
Though I did not
expect your rude
interruption, the outcome
remains unchanged.
I shall finish you here.
No.
Wait, Caster.
I want to attach one condition
to my joining your forces.
A condition?
I offered my freedom
without resistance.
My price is that
you let them leave.
For all your words and
actions, you're rather soft.
No.
I merely thought it would
be wrong for a Heroic Spirit
to cut down his
heartbroken former Master.
It's strange to hear common
decency from a traitor's mouth.
Very well. I shall let them go.
But if they ever get
in my way again...
Of course.
Fools who would embrace a hopeless
fight deserve to be cut down without mercy.
Let's go.
For now, he's right.
Any anger you might hold
for me is misplaced, Rin.
This woman is simply the
superior Master. That's all.
I side with the most powerful.
That's true.
But you'll regret it.
I'll never quit.
You hear me?
I'll defeat Caster
and take you back.
And when I do,
no amount of apology
will be enough.
That's what you get for
pulling a stunt like that!
Get some rest!
No, let's get back to my
place as soon as possible.
It doesn't hurt that much.
You can't be serious!
Don't tell me it doesn't hurt,
not with an injury like that!
Hey, are you listening?
Why is this even happening?
Couldn't you tell right away
that the church wasn't safe?
I'm not that stupid.
Of course I could!
Then you should have
turned right around, idiot!
How could you try
projecting with those injuries?
You should've known
it'd just make them worse!
And now you're telling
me you aren't in pain?
What is wrong with you?
Well, you're hurting
worse than I am, right?
So let's go home.
You can gripe and
moan once we get back.
Uh...
I can't believe this.
A guy made me cry.
T-Tohsaka, my hand...
Shut up.
You're going to
make this right, jerk.
Listen,
don't you dare turn around.
If you see my face,
I'll get really mad.
Archer was right.
I should have defeated Caster when I
had the chance, no matter what it took.
I'm not whining or anything,
but I always mess up
the most important thing.
I can handle the second or
third most important thing easily.
But I always mess up
the most important one.
I can't only blame him
for going over to her side.
Sheesh.
After all I said,
I suddenly found
myself cornered.
I think this is where you're
supposed to say, "By what?"
Oh.
Then, cornered by what?
By you. Your words made me realize
I'd failed, and I got even more depressed.
That's only temporary, right?
You haven't done anything
to beat yourself up over.
Why not?
We're in this mess because
my strategy was so wrong.
That just means you
failed at one thing.
But that doesn't mean
you're wrong, Tohsaka.
To be honest, you look
blindingly brilliant to me.
I don't regret things, either.
I believe what I've
done to be right, but...
That belief is a
mess of patches.
But once you get that
regret out of your system,
I bet you'll pay
them back twice over.
By the way, why did you save me?
Huh? How did you get that?
You can have it back.
I have another pendant
just like it at my house.
After Lancer nearly killed me at
school, I found it lying next to me.
I've had it ever since.
You have one just like it?
Huh? Did I say
something strange?
No, not really.
Anyway, why would this be
a reason for you to save me?
Well...
The truth is, that
was an afterthought.
If I must confess,
I've always been attracted to
this girl named Tohsaka Rin.
Then, inconvenient as it was...
When I finally got around to
talking to her, I fell for her even more.
So before I knew it, I had already
jumped down there without thinking.
H-Hey, if you go around blurting
out things like that without thinking,
people will get the wrong idea!
I really do have
feelings for you!
Y-You jerk! You enormous jerk!
Thanks for coming to my rescue.
You're a lifesaver.
If I am destined to
turn to ash and bones
Then I want to sing of
happiness and despair
While I still can
Our fate for the days to come
Is fighting an inch from death
With dreams in our hearts
Once you cried at night
But a better future for
us was always possible
Quietude awaits you
We can find that gleaming hill
Ring your bell
Towards your own horizon
I appreciate your
thoughtfulness, but before that...
It works best when the
raw materials are fresh.
Could we work
with other Masters?
You are about to die here,
so is that any of your concern?
The Princess of Colchis
Next Time